

# CHE NASRI EZUAN BIN CHE YUSOFF

C-2-50B, Jln SP5/4, Seksyen 5, Taman Serdang Perdana, 43300 Seri Kembangan, Selangor, Malaysia +60136405720 nasriezuan@gmail.com

## **PERSONAL PROFILE**

A former External Auditor, Group Assistant Finance Manager and Accounting Technical Advisor at a consultation firm. Background includes appointed as an auditor at Ernst & Young (EY) with exposure in various industries such as property developer, construction, shipping, trading, manufacturing, REIT, oil and gas, energy and was seconded to EY Aberdeen, subsequently hired by a big property developer company as Group Assistant Finance Manager and leading the team on all the tax matters and accounting function within the organization. Fluency in English and Bahasa Malaysia. Have experience awarded as Malaysia's best student for Matriculation program. Technically proficient in Microsoft Office, Biztrak, UBS and IFCA Accounting Software.

## **EDUCATION**

2006 – 2010 University of Malaya , Malaysia Bachelor in Accounting (3.14/4.00) 2nd class upper

2005 – 2006 Malacca Matriculation College, Malaysia
Matriculation program (4.00/4.00)
Malaysia' Best Student Award for Economic subject, Ministry of Education
Malaysia' Excellent Student Award, Ministry of Education

# **RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE**

January 2016 – December 2016 One GST Solution LLP, Damansara, Malaysia, Accounting Technical Advisor

- Responsible to advise the firm partner on the accounting technical issues.
- Reviewed and provide the solution and recommendation on the issues addressed by the clients to comply with GST regulation.
- Actively involved in the meeting with client to expedite the deliverables.
- Assisted firm partner on the accounting matters especially when dealt with various industries which I have expertise with.
- Actively advised and update the firm partner and client on the latest amendment of Companies Act 1965,
   Income Tax Act 1967, Malaysian Financial Reporting Standards and Financial Reporting Standards.

- Delivered Group performance and sales result on forthnightly and monthly basis besides the ratio analysis.
- Monitored the performance and responsible for Group budgeting and managing the cost.
- Led the finance team for all the companies within the Group during the financial audit.
- Led the finance team for corporate tax and indirect tax (Sales Tax and Good & Service Tax) and a trainer for non-finance staff.
- Developed tax planning models and restructuring mechanism.
- Managed complex and intercompany transaction issues and provided the solution to respective Finance Manager.
- Implemented cost effective policies on the operation upon adoption of Goods and Services Tax.
- Maintained the completeness and efficiency in recording of accounting works and the documentation system.

June 2010 – December 2013 Ernst & Young, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia, External Auditor

- Developed audit planning for allocation of budgeted cost and the deadline.
- Identified audit risk and test on effectiveness and efficiencies of internal control.
- Developed proper communication with client and acts as liason between audit partner and client.
- Performed substantive procedure and analytical review.
- Highlighted on the accounting issues and compliance with Companies Act 1965 and applicable accounting standards.
- Reviewed working papers and proposed solution on the issues prior for submission to audit partner.

## **VOLUNTEERING**

May 2015 – August 2015 Belum Rainforest Resort, Perak, Malaysia, Finance Rescue Team

- Led the team to finalise the management accounts for audit and corporate tax. (upon resignation of Finance Manager)
- Managed to assist Resort to recover the long outstanding debts.
- Developed new accounting system for the Resort.

## **CLUBS & SOCIETIES**

June 2010 – December 2013 Ernst & Young, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia, EY Staff Club

- Participated in IAFG Tug of War vice leader for EY team
- Participated in Annual Dinner
- Participated in technical training

## **QUALIFICATIONS & AWARDS**

- **Sept 2006 Ministry of Education Award:** Malaysia' Best and Excellent Student Award for Matriculation program. The matriculation program takes 1 year to finish as perquisite for Bachelor Degree program.
- **Feb 2011 May 2011 Secondment to EY Aberdeen:** I was selected by EY Aberdeen to perform the audit for British Petroleum of Companies and being a representative from Malaysia.
- June 2014 Awesome award EMKAY Group: I was awarded for demonstrate the core values of the companies and brought paradigm to the Finance Team.

#### **KEY SKILLS**

#### Microsoft Office

• I was able to utilised resources in the Microsoft Office tools software with the great knowledge of shortcut keys and tricks to perform the works efficiently and prepare the presentation materials creatively.

## Biztrak and IFCA Accounting Software (complied with GST)

• The Biztrak software is general accounting software that I used to review routinely while the IFCA software is specifically for property development accounting. I was able to review the works with the user friendly tools and utilised the technologies provided. I was a trainer for the accounting software for new staff in my company.

## Group Accounting and fundamental of accounting

• I have excellent Group Accounts knowledge and consolidation of accounts expert. I was able to consolidate 59 conglomerate subsidiaries and successfully complete the accounts ahead before the deadline and submitted to SSM without any penalties.

## GST knowledge and fixed the issues related to submission

 When I was in the commercial company, I am the one who reviewed the accuracy and completeness of the transaction for each subsidiaries plus active companies that registered with RMCD. Any delayed in the process to reclaim the refund, I manage to solve for any inquiries by RMCD.

#### **LANGUAGES**

- English (Fluent, Business and Conversational)
- Bahasa Malaysia (Mother Tongue, Business and Conversational)
- Arabic (Beginner)

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Malaysia Financial Reporting Standard(MFRS)
- Financial Reporting Standard (FRS)
- Private Entity Reporting Standard (PERS)
- Companies Act 1965 (with latest amendment)
- Bursa Malaysia requirement
- Housing and Development Act (Controlling and License) 1966
- Goods and Services Tax Act 2014
- Income Tax Act 1967

#### **REFERENCE**

- Mohd Firdaus bin Mohamad
   Partner of One GST Solution LLP
   Known since 2006
   017-936 8624
- Musdi bin Ismail
   Finance Manager, EMKAY Group
   Known since 2013
   019-359 7640